All right. To grab the form on one line,
the first thing we need to do is we need
to grab this form. And it has a nice ID
right here. So, we're going to say let
my form equal document doquery selector.
And we're going to look for um login
form. The the element that has login
form as its ID. Once we've done that, we
can now turn it into a form data object.
The form data object
is very similar to a normal object. So
you can get attributes
based on their keys and their values. So
I could say let form data equal new and
the keyword new is really important
here. And then you're going to use this
form data. And you'll know it's the
right one because it'll start with a
capital F and then start with a capital
D. And then you'll put parenthesis. And
it says, okay, I need you to give me a
form. So we'll access the form. And now
we have all of the form data stored
here. So um if I console.log that for
you
um when you submit the form I'll put
test test and hit submit you can see it
logs out this form data object. And if
we open it up it has get attributes. So
if we do form data.get username and save
it and we type test test and hit submit
then we get the word test. If we type
username here and hit submit, we get the
word username. And so you can use
this.get to grab items. And how is it
grabbing them? Well, it's grabbing them
by the name that you've put on your
input field. So if you put a name of
password then and then you access it
using password form data.get password,
then you'll be able to grab that
password that we've put. So if we hit
submit now um oh if we save it if we
type test and password and hit submit
you can see that password is logged out.
All right well I promised you this on
one line. So could this be simplified to
one line? And the answer is yes it
could. So we could say let form data
equal new form data document query
selector
hashtag login form
and then
we put a semicolon and now we no longer
need the previous two lines of code. So
what this does is it gives us a form
data object and we can access attributes
by using this.get get. And in the next
video, I'll show you how we could then
use that to make a post request.